Class Photograph Collection BCMS.0029
Brooklyn Collection
Class Photograph Collection
1904-2002
Center for Brooklyn History
BCMS.0029
0.72 Cubic Feet in 1 flat box
The Class Photograph Collection consists of group photographs from Brooklyn schools, spanning the years 1904-2002.
Accruals
Accruals are expected; the finding aid will be updated as more class photographs are acquired.
Provenance
This is a synthetic collection that has had and will continue to have accruals. The original group was purchased from Brian Merlis in April of 2013.
Related Materials
Also at the Brooklyn Collection:
Clippings files arranged by school name
Ephemera files arranged by school name
Yearbook Collection
High School Newspaper Collection
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by school name.
Access
Collection is located in the Brooklyn Collection at the Central Branch at Grand Army Plaza. The collection may only be used in the library and is not available through interlibrary loan. Requests to view the collection must be made at least 48 hours in advance of visit.
Scope and Contents
This small collection documents graduating classes at various public and private schools in Brooklyn. Additionally, there are two photographs of the staff of Boys High School's student publication, the Recorder. Some photographs list student names on the verso, but most do not.
Boys' High School (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.); Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Private schools -- New York (State) -- New York.; Public schools -- New York (State) -- New York.
- Alexander Hamilton Vocational High School, 1947 June (Box 2)
- Arthur S. Somers JHS, 1941-1952 (Box 1)
  General
  Class 9BR, June 1941.
  Class 9B5, June 1942. Winifred Kaplan second row, 4th from right.
  Class 9-SP1, June 1949.
  Class 9-SP1, June 1952.
- Boys High School, 1904-1940 (Box 1, Flat file folder BCMS.0029)
  1906; 1919 June [oversize]; 1940 January.
  Staff of the Boys High School Recorder, c. 1904 and 1906.
- Boody Junior High School, 1939 June (Box 1)
  Class 9B5
- Brooklyn College of Pharmacy, undated (Box 1)
- Dewey Junior High School, 1945 (Box 2)
  Class 9B1
- Intermediate School 227 (E.B. Shallow), 1934 January (Box 1)
- Intermediate School 252K, 2002 (Box 2)
- Junior High School 66, 1937 January (Box 1)
- Junior High School 84, 1930 (Box 1)
  Class RD1
- Our Lady of Guadalupe School, 1935 (Box 2)
- Public School 26, 1936 January (Box 1)
  Class 8B1
- Public School 40, 1937 January (Box 2)
- Public School 44, 1916 (Box 1)
- Public School 50, 1921 January, 1923 January (Box 1)
- Public School 64, 1923 (Box 1)
  Class 8B graduation photo and class play photo.
  Note: These items are stored with the Bella Gordon P.S. 64 Collection (BCMS.0042).
- Public School 76, 1951 April (Box 2)
- Public School 84 (Glenmore Junior High School), 1924 January (Box 1)
- Public School 89, 1924 June (Box 2)
- Public School 104, 1917 June, 1918 February (Box 1)
  June 1917: 2nd row, first person on left is Rafael Vilhelm Forslund, born 6 December 1900, Forsby, Uusikaarlepyy, Vassa, Finland. Died 6 June 1951, Brooklyn.
  February 1918: 3rd row, seventh person from left is Hildar Johanna Forsland, born 22 August 1903, Forsby, Finland. Resided in Brooklyn until 1979 and died in Whiting, New Jersey.
  Both arrived in New York with their parents and other siblings 15 July 1909.
- Public School 114, 1918 February (Box 1)
- Public School 115, 1927 January (Box 1)
- Public School 130, 1944 January (Box 1)
- Public School 136 (copy of 1914 original), 2016 (Box 2)
- Public School 145, 1922 June (Box 1)
- Public School 167, 1930 June (Box 1)
- Public School 175, 1955-1962 (Box 2)
  One folder containing 15 8x10 class photographs and candid classroom photographs.
- Public School 178, 1931 June (Box 1)
- Public School 193, 1950 June (Box 1)
- Public School 201, 1937 June (Box 1)
- Public School 238, 1942 June (Box 1)
- Unknown Catholic school, undated (Box 1)